<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Jared Taylor</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.jaredtaylor.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.jaredtaylor.org</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 01:46:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>http://www.jaredtaylor.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/N-5544bc01v1_site_icon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Jared Taylor</title>
	<link>http://www.jaredtaylor.org</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Foreword to the Kindle edition of Paved with Good Intentions</title>
		<link>http://www.jaredtaylor.org/2014/06/foreword-to-the-kindle-edition-of-paved-with-good-intentions/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 15:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jaredtaylor.org/?p=11</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Jared Taylor, VDARE, June 21, 2014 Again, I must begin with thanks to the people who made this edition possible. We live in evil times, and they have asked that I not mention them by name and I have reluctantly complied, but it is they and they alone who have kept this book alive. Sadly, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jared Taylor, VDARE, June 21, 2014</p>
<p><span id="more-11"></span><br />
<a href="http://www.jaredtaylor.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/paved-with-good-intentions.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-5" src="http://www.jaredtaylor.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/paved-with-good-intentions.jpg" alt="Paved with Good Intentions" width="180" height="269" /></a></p>
<p>Again, I must begin with thanks to the people who made this edition possible. We live in evil times, and they have asked that I not mention them by name and I have reluctantly complied, but it is they and they alone who have kept this book alive.</p>
<p>Sadly, preservation of older books may be more important than ever. In the preface to the 2004 edition of <em>Paved With Good Intentions</em>, I mentioned half a dozen books that had appeared after mine in the 1990s and that seemed to presage a breakthrough on race. That breakthrough never came. The new century has seen an almost complete retreat by the mainstream press from anything but orthodoxy. Gregory Cochran and Henry Harpending’s 2009 book, <em>The 10,000 Year Explosion,</em> is a startling exception.</p>
<p>Why did publishers show the white feather? It is part of the new Dark Age that has fallen across the entire Western world. Doctrinaire egalitarians are now so desperate and vindictive–and still so powerful–that few people dare challenge them openly, and race and nationalism are not the only fields in which dissent is banned. We are to believe that not only are races equal but that religions, cultures, nations, sexes, and “life-styles” are equal. Merely to point out objective differences is dangerous; to state preferences is scandalous.</p>
<p>Today’s orthodoxy is not enforced by state censors–it would be better if it were. When the government officially suppresses dissent, the enemy is clear. What we have is a system of self-censorship, in which everyone knows the rules and censors himself. High-profile, ritual shaming of dissidents reminds us where the boundaries lie.</p>
<p>In the area of race alone, there have been many shamings. Jason Richwine, Jack Hunter, Sam Francis, Scott McConnell, John Derbyshire, Joseph Sobran, Robert Weissberg, Kevin Lamb, Frank Borzellieri, Leif Parsell, and many others have lost their jobs because of “racism.” John O’Sullivan, Peter Brimelow, Patrick Buchanan, and James Watson have all suffered professionally for excessive truth telling.</p>
<p>The case of James Watson vividly demonstrates the tyrannical power of the egalitarian establishment. In 2007, he told London’s <em>The Sunday Times</em> newspaper that he was “inherently gloomy about the prospect of Africa,” adding that “[all] our social policies are based on the fact that their intelligence is the same as ours–whereas all the testing says not really.” [The elementary DNA of Dr Watson, By Charlotte Hunt-Grubbe, TimesOnLine. October 14, 2007]</p>
<p>Dr. Watson, co-discoverer of the double helix and Nobel laureate, was probably the most famous scientist in the world. He scraped and backtracked, even cravenly saying that “there is no scientific basis for such a belief,” yet these few dissident words ended his 39-year career at Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory.</p>
<p>Sex differences are quicksand. In 2005, Lawrence Summers resigned as president of Harvard, after fury over his suggestion that one reason so few women are in science is that their minds may not be identical to those of men. He offered this merely as a conjecture and hoped to be proven wrong, but even as a conjecture this was too much for Harvard University.</p>
<p>Just this year, outgoing Secretary of Defense Leon Panetta announced that America will put women in combat. Do American soldiers think this is a good idea? I know from personal communication with people in the military that many think this is insanity, but I am not aware of a single serving officer who publicly opposed Mr. Panetta. That would be career suicide.</p>
<p>In today’s atmosphere, therefore, <em>Paved With Good Intentions</em> could not be published, and even if only for historical reasons it is instructive to read what was publishable in 1992.</p>
<p>Twenty years ago, I thought that the evils and absurdities I was pointing out in this book would be reformed within my lifetime. Now, I’m not so sure. This is not to say that Americans are blind to these evils and absurdities. As I note below, more Americans that ever have a clear understanding of race. However, American institutions continue to ignore the obvious, and Congress, the courts, major media, and universities have the combined power to suppress common sense.</p>
<p>It was the suppression of common sense that prompted outrage over New York City’s stop-and-frisk policy. Police questioned people they thought looked suspicious, and Mayor Michael Bloomberg believed this stopped a great deal of crime. [Stop-and-Frisk Policy ‘Saves Lives,’ Mayor Tells Black Congregation, By Kate Taylor, June 10, 2012] The New York Civil Liberties Union and other groups charged discrimination, however, because blacks and Hispanics were more likely to be stopped than whites.</p>
<p>Curiously, it did not seem to bother them that the police were stopping men–young men. There was sharper sex and age discrimination than race discrimination. No one cared about that, because everyone knows that young men are vastly more criminal than old women, and that it is a waste of time to stop grandmothers.</p>
<p>And yet, the statistical basis for stopping blacks and Hispanics was exactly the same as for stopping young men: They commit the most crime. People understand basic probability about age or sex, but their minds stop working when it comes to race.</p>
<p>I pointed this out in 1992; there has been no progress in 20 years.</p>
<p>Congress has made no progress either. The No Child Left Behind Act of 2001 was supposed to close the racial gaps in school achievement and ensure that every student in America could read and do math at the “proficient” level by 2014. These ridiculous goals–and stiff penalties for not meeting them–prompted widespread cheating on tests that led to criminal indictments of 35 teachers in the heavily-black Atlanta school district. [Grand jury indicts 35 in Georgia school cheating scandal, By Chelsea J. Carter, CNN, March 29, 2013 ]</p>
<p>By 2013, the Department of Education had granted waivers to no fewer than 39 states and the District of Columbia because they had no hope of meeting the act’s foolish requirements. [Arne Duncan gives No Child Left Behind waivers to California district, By Lyndsey Layton, Washington Post, August 6, 2013]</p>
<p>It finally dawned on the state of Florida that if not a single school in the whole country can eliminate racial gaps, it is wrong to punish teachers who cannot achieve the impossible. In 2013, the state set more realistic goals: highest for Asians, lowest for blacks–and the Southern Poverty Law Center promptly filed a complaint with the U.S. Department of Justice, claiming that the new goals “violate fundamental civil rights.”</p>
<p>Any glimmering of race realism must be snuffed out.</p>
<p>One of the arguments I made in 1992 was that whites are terrified of being thought “racist.” Twenty years later nothing has changed.</p>
<p>In 2010, former President George W. Bush said that the worst moment in his eight years in office was a tossed-off remark by a black rapper named Kanye West, who said the President did not send enough relief to New Orleans after Hurricane Katrina because he didn’t “care about black people.” Mr. Bush had some bad patches in his presidency–the September 11 terrorist attacks, the invasion of Iraq on false pretenses, the Abu Ghraib scandal, the crash of 2008–but being called a racist by a black entertainer was the worst thing that happened to him as president.</p>
<p>How much do whites trim their actions–even their thoughts–for fear of being called names? What honest, useful things might President Bush have done if he were not a mental hostage to blacks?</p>
<p>As I noted in 1992, even absurd accusations of “racism” have power only because whites give them that power. Twenty years later, George Bush still doesn’t understand that.</p>
<p>In 1992 I gave many examples of ordinary people–not even dissidents–who had lost their jobs on account of “racism.”</p>
<p>They still lose their jobs. In 2013, celebrity cook Paula Deen’s program was scrubbed from the Food Network because she admitted that in the 1980s she had used the word “nigger.”</p>
<p>Likewise in 2013, two white contestants in a “reality” television program called “Big Brother 15” were fired from their day jobs for such things as referring to a homosexual as a “queer,” and telling an Asian girl to “shut up and make some rice.” [See What Racist Remarks by Two ‘Big Brother’ Contestants Led to Their Firings Back Home, By Erica Rit, <em>The Blaze</em>, July 8, 2013]</p>
<p>I noted in 1992 that it is only whites who must always govern their tongues. In 2012, there were no repercussions when Jamie Foxx promoted his new movie, Django Unchained, by saying, “I save my wife, and I kill all the white people in the movie. How great is that? And how black is that?” [Jamie Foxx Jokes About Killing &#8216;All The White People&#8217; In His New Movie, By Noel Sheppard, December 10, 2012] In 2013, the black congressman Charles Rangel said that the Tea Party “is the same group we faced in the South with those white crackers and the dogs and the police.” [Charlie Rangel: Tea Party Is &#8216;Same Group&#8217; Of &#8216;White Crackers&#8217; Who Fought Civil Rights, TPM, August 2, 2013.]</p>
<p>I’m sure Mr. Foxx meant to glory in the fantasy of killing whites, and Mr. Rangel meant to offend Tea Party members, but their remarks caused barely a ripple.</p>
<p>This book is full of examples of double standards. Whites–but only whites–must avoid the faintest hint of “insensitivity.” Whites–but only whites–must never be proud of their race. Whites–but only whites–must never act as if they have legitimate group interests, even though other groups openly organize in opposition to those interests.</p>
<p>There has been no change in 20 years.</p>
<p>How long will this go on? Another 20 years? The great contradiction of American race relations is that it is whites who still make the rules. Blacks could have howled themselves hoarse over Paula Deen, but they would have quickly stopped howling if the white people who run the Food Network had ignored them. It was white people who fired James Watson, Jason Richwine, and John Derbyshire; not blacks.</p>
<p>It was not even blacks who most loudly criticized these dissidents; it was whites. If whites wanted to, they could make life very hard for Charles Rangel and Jamie Foxx, but they do not dare. And we have to listen to Al Sharpton, Jesse Jackson, and Janet Murguia only because white media executives give them a microphone.</p>
<p>Whites do not lack the power to defend their interests. They lack the will, and it is unprecedented in human history that a majority people should abandon its interests.</p>
<p>Sometime in the mid- to late 20th century, almost all white governments capitulated. The most striking change was their willingness to accept displacement of their people by non-white immigrants. In the United States, whites are now expected to become a minority by 2042. Western Europe, Australia, and Canada, are headed the same way. Only Eastern Europe, which the Cold War protected from the egalitarian folly of the West, has retained an instinctive sense of ethnic and national interests. But for how long?</p>
<p>This is, to me, the tragedy and mystery of our age. Why have whites given up the will to survive as a distinct people?</p>
<p>There is no lack of theories: the demoralizing effect of two world wars, the machinations of Jews, the universalist doctrine of Christianity, materialism, individualism. I do not believe any or all of them fully explain why whites abandoned so basic, so ancient, so legitimate, and so noble an instinct as the preservation of their own people.</p>
<p>One of the consequences of displacement, of course, is that whites will stop making the rules. In America, the 2012 Presidential elections were an unmistakable sign of what is to come. Although Mitt Romney won 60 percent of the white vote–more than enough to win if whites still dominated the electorate–he lost because the 26 percent of the electorate that is non-white voted overwhelmingly for the non-white candidate. In other words, because they had admitted millions of non-whites into their country, whites did not get the President they wanted.</p>
<p>What will America be like when whites stop making the rules? This is a pressing question that few ask and even fewer answer, but let me try. The government already requires discrimination against whites, and calls it “affirmative action.” The government already bans race-neutral job qualifications that have a “disparate impact” on protected minorities. Universities already encourage every race but whites to start student unions and activist groups. We already have a media that agonizes over white misbehavior but ignores brutal anti-white crime.</p>
<p>When blacks and Hispanics start making the rules, they will not end “affirmative action;” they will expand it. They might well correct the problem of “white privilege” with a tax that only whites must pay. White jurors obviously cannot make fair decisions–look at the mess they made of George Zimmerman’s trial–so there could be rules to ensure that juries never have white majorities. Leadership roles in Congress could be reserved for non-whites to ensure fairness. Tax-exemptions help maintain white privilege, so all non-profits could be made to show how they benefit non-whites. The “racism” of capitalism could be curbed by making sure no company has a majority-white board of directors. Residential segregation could be solved by giving non-white home buyers an automatic bidding advantage, like the advantage the Small Business Administration already gives non-whites who bid on government contracts. I have every confidence that Sonia Sotomayor and her fellow justices of the future would find these measures Constitutional–if, indeed, our new rulers still bother with such Caucasian niceties as constitutionality.</p>
<p>Is this paranoid raving? Just imagine how the Black or Hispanic Congressional Caucuses would vote on any of these things today, and ask yourself why a majority-black and -Hispanic Congress would vote any differently. And for the rest of us, far from Washington, life will become darker, more violent, and more corrupt, as whites flee to the dwindling patches of land where they are still a desperate majority.</p>
<p>This will be our future unless whites regain a sense of identity. I have spent the last 25 years trying to rekindle that identity, trying to awaken whites to this looming crisis. For more than 20 years I published the dissident monthly magazine American Renaissance, which has now moved to the web at AmRen.com. In 2011, I also published a book called <em>White Identity</em>, which is more explicit than this one about the need for–well–white identity. If you found <em>Paved With Good Intentions</em> useful I think you will find <em>White Identity</em> useful, too.</p>
<p>There has been unquestionable progress in the development of white identity. Twenty-five years ago, anyone who doubted racial orthodoxy had to look in dusty corners of libraries or write off to obscure post office boxes to find undeceived information. Now, the Internet has scores of dissident websites, there are organizations that hold public conferences about the interests of whites, and there are racially-oriented publishing houses that bring out the excellent books commercial publishers are afraid to touch.</p>
<p>What encourages me most is the number of young people who, by their 20s, have a fully developed understanding of race. I was in my 40s before I saw what they see. Likewise, the public comments on “mainstream” websites are proof that a huge number of Americans are not fooled by the media. Nothing better demonstrates the difference between elite or published opinion and public opinion. This is why our rulers are so desperate to punish dissenters. This is why the publishing breakthrough of the 1990s had to be stopped.</p>
<p>Orthodoxy is still immensely powerful, but it has no moral and intellectual foundations. Whenever there is real debate between dissidents and apparatchiks, the apparatchiks lose–and more and more people know it. That is why our rulers never permit debate. That is why, ultimately, they will fall even if there is no debate.</p>
<p>The French author Guillaume Faye has written that if the whites now in their 20s fail to act, they and their civilization are doomed. I am confident they will act.</p>
<p>Source: http://www.vdare.com/articles/foreword-to-the-kindle-edition-of-paved-with-good-intentions</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On The Menu: Opposing Racial Diversity</title>
		<link>http://www.jaredtaylor.org/2007/03/on-the-menu-opposing-racial-diversity/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 15:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jaredtaylor.org/?p=9</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Peter Duffy interviews Jared Taylor for the Chronicle Herald (Halifax), March 8, 2007 HE ORDERS the fish and chips; I settle for a cup of coffee. The waitress leaves with our order and Jared Taylor leans back, catching his breath. “The media scrum gave you a pretty rough time back there,” I remark. He shrugs [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Peter Duffy interviews Jared Taylor for the <em>Chronicle Herald</em> (Halifax), March 8, 2007<span id="more-9"></span></p>
<p>HE ORDERS the fish and chips; I settle for a cup of coffee.</p>
<p>The waitress leaves with our order and Jared Taylor leans back, catching his breath.</p>
<p>“The media scrum gave you a pretty rough time back there,” I remark.</p>
<p>He shrugs and smiles.</p>
<p>“That was the only time I saw you rattled,” I press him. “When that TV reporter asked you whether you’d ever had gone out with a person of colour, you were rattled.”</p>
<p>“I was annoyed,” he corrects. “There are certain things I wouldn’t talk about, like my eating habits and my bowel habits.”</p>
<p>It’s been a long Tuesday morning for this controversial American magazine editor and self-styled race realist.</p>
<p>This is the second time in as many months Jared Taylor has been invited to Halifax to debate racial diversity.</p>
<p>It’s his contention that nations like Canada, which promote racial harmony, are deluding themselves. This man believes strongly that racial diversity is a weakness and shouldn’t be encouraged because it leads to social unrest and violence.</p>
<p>He feels people should be free of government interference, free to make their own associations. He says forced integration flies in the face of the reality we’re all tribal in nature and prefer the company of those like ourselves.</p>
<p>Twice now, he’s had the rug pulled from under him when he’s tried to speak at a Halifax university.</p>
<p>The first time was in January at Dalhousie University. The second was this week, when he flew in to debate racial diversity with Saint Mary’s University philosophy professor Peter March, another champion of free speech but with the opposing view.</p>
<p>In the end, the two men squared off on radio station AM 920/CJCH with Hotline host Rick Howe moderating.</p>
<p>The 90-minute event was very civilized and ended in what felt like a draw. Now it’s lunchtime and Jared and I are back at his downtown hotel, where Peter has dropped us.</p>
<p>“I don’t understand why people are intent on demonizing me,” says the 55-year-old father of two daughters.</p>
<p>He tells me these two trouble-plagued trips to Halifax are the only visits he’s ever made to Canada. He says he has spoken on hundreds of radio stations and numerous campuses in the U.S. without any trouble.</p>
<p>“I’m not treated like the devil incarnate like I am here,” he says.</p>
<p>“It must really get to you after a while,” I reply.</p>
<p>He nods. “It’s wearing to be constantly treated as a moral defective.”</p>
<p>“So why put yourself through it?”</p>
<p>The Virginian confesses that he doesn’t enjoy doing it but plugs away because he feels it must be done.</p>
<p>“I’m an entirely ordinary man who cares because, ultimately, our civilization depends on it.”</p>
<p>He asks me my opinion of the debate.</p>
<p>I tell him I came away confused. “Peter March would make a case for racial diversity and I’d agree with it wholeheartedly. But then you’d say something and I could recognize myself in your anti-diversity argument.”</p>
<p>I tell Jared that, being from England, it was difficult not to bring some of my tribal European attitudes with me when I came to Canada, 40-odd years ago. Most of them didn’t last long.</p>
<p>“I came to realize that Canada truly represents the best chance this world has of creating a decent society where everyone can get along.”</p>
<p>“But why risk it?” he interjects. “What if it doesn’t work? You had a delightful white society here.”</p>
<p>But it can work, I persist. “I spent six years in Fort McMurray. Thousands of us came from all over Canada and all over the world. We were all equal and we all got along just fine. We worked side by side and we built a city from nothing.”</p>
<p>“Was it all white people or mostly white people?” he asks.</p>
<p>I think back. “Nearly all white.”</p>
<p>“Would it have worked if it had been 20 per cent black,” he challenges, “or 20 per cent lesbian or …?”</p>
<p>I hold up my hand. “I don’t want to think that way,” I say. “I need to see past a man’s skin colour.”</p>
<p>He chuckles. “Peter, you’re starting to sound like a Marxist.”</p>
<p>“So what advice have you come to Halifax to share?” I ask.</p>
<p>“If racial diversity weakens,” he replies, “then don’t add to it through immigration.” And stop forcing people into each other’s company through non-discrimination laws.</p>
<p>Jared glances down at his half-eaten lunch and then at his watch. He has to leave for another media interview.</p>
<p>He reaches for the bill and then pauses. “Government,” he reflects, “looks over every employer’s shoulder in the U.S. and Canada and makes sure there’s a certain mix. The next step will be to tell you who you should marry.”</p>
<p>“To be continued,” I say as we shake hands.</p>
<p>“To be continued,” he promises.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.herald.ns.ca/Search/563234.html"><b>Original article</b></a></p>
<p>Email Peter Duffy at <a href="mailto:pduffy@herald.ca">pduffy@herald.ca</a>. (Posted on March 8, 2007)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Real American Dilemma Race, Immigration, and the Future of America</title>
		<link>http://www.jaredtaylor.org/1998/04/the-real-american-dilemma-race-immigration-and-the-future-of-america/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 1998 15:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jaredtaylor.org/?p=13</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Buy this book on-line here. Race is still the American dilemma. This is partly because Americans dare not speak frankly about it. This book is different. Its contributors refuse to be intimidated by accusations of “racism.” They address the burning issues of our time: Why is integration not working? Is Third World immigration good for [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure class="pull-right"><a href="http://www.jaredtaylor.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/real_american_dilemma.gif"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-6" src="http://www.jaredtaylor.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/real_american_dilemma-209x300.gif" alt="The Real American Dilemma" width="209" height="300" /></a><figcaption><a href="http://store.amren.com/catalog/books/the-real-american-dilemma/">Buy this book on-line here</a>.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Race is still the American dilemma. This is partly because Americans dare not speak frankly about it. This book is different. Its contributors refuse to be intimidated by accusations of “racism.” They address the burning issues of our time:</p>
<p><span id="more-13"></span></p>
<ul>
<li>Why is integration not working?</li>
<li>Is Third World immigration good for America?</li>
<li>Are whites destined to become a minority?</li>
<li>Why is there so much black crime?</li>
</ul>
<p>Includes essays by:</p>
<ul>
<li>Prof. Philippe Rushton</li>
<li>Dr. Samuel Francis</li>
<li>Prof. Michael Levin</li>
<li>Prof. Glayde Whitney</li>
<li>Jared Taylor</li>
<li>Prof. Michael Hart</li>
<li>Fr. James Thornton</li>
<li>Dr. Wayne Lutton</li>
</ul>
<p>This book will make you think. If you care about America it will make you act. It is a collection that brings together eight of the most thoughtful people writing about race today.</p>
<p><b>From the Introduction:</b></p>
<blockquote><p>More and more Americans believe that the liberal approach to race relations has been a catastrophe, but they are loathe to say so openly. This is because the liberal analysis has been an accepted part of the intellectual landscape for so long that it is essentially unassailable. Race is, in fact, the great taboo. There is no other subject on which private opinion diverges so widely from public pronouncement.</p>
<p><small>Jared Taylor</small></p></blockquote>
<p><b>From the reviews:</b></p>
<blockquote><p>I think <i>The Real American Dilemma</i> … ought to be recommended reading for every American concerned about the future of the republic — especially if you are white.</p>
<p><small>Ken Hamblin, The Denver Post </small></p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>The well-researched views on race put forth in The Real American Dilemma are an indispensable volume for those wanting the unfettered truth on the most sensitive issue of our time.</p>
<p><small>Frank Borzellieri, Queens Ledger </small></p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Conservatives weary of liberal half-truths and outright lies about that most contentious of subjects, race, will enjoy The Real American Dilemma … This book is chock full of excellent articles from a conservative viewpoint.</p>
<p><small>Michael Masters, The Citizens Informer </small></p></blockquote>
<table class="table table-striped">
<caption>Additional information</caption>
<tbody>
<tr>
<th>Weight</th>
<td>0.5 lbs</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<th>Dimensions</th>
<td>8.3 × 5.4 × 0.5 in</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<th>Page Count</th>
<td>152 pages</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<th>ISBN-10</th>
<td>0965638308</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<th>ISBN-13</th>
<td>978-0965638302</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<th>Publisher</th>
<td>New Century Books; 1st ptg. edition (April 1, 1998)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review of Paved with Good Intentions</title>
		<link>http://www.jaredtaylor.org/1993/01/review-of-paved-with-good-intentions/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 1993 15:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jaredtaylor.org/?p=10</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[by Peter Brimelow National Review, January 18, 1993 “WAS THE MUGGER black?” asked my wife sympathetically. As a Canadian newly arrived in Manhattan, she honestly didn’t know that you must Never Ask. Her hostess, caught off balance in mid-crime story, admitted that he was. Then she hurriedly covered herself: of course, she said, this meant [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i>by Peter Brimelow</i></p>
<p><b> National Review, January 18, 1993</b></p>
<p><span id="more-10"></span></p>
<p>“WAS THE MUGGER black?” asked my wife sympathetically. As a Canadian newly arrived in Manhattan, she honestly didn’t know that you must Never Ask. Her hostess, caught off balance in mid-crime story, admitted that he was. Then she hurriedly covered herself: of course, she said, this meant nothing.</p>
<p>Besides being a Canadian, however, my wife was and still is in some respects invincibly innocent. And now she was really puzzled. “But aren’t most muggers in New York black?” she inquired. Her hostess was outraged. “I don’t believe that,” she snapped.</p>
<p>The single greatest strength of <a href="http://www.jaredtaylor.org/" title="About Mr. Taylor">Jared Taylor</a>’s <a href="/paved-with-good-intentions.php"><i>Paved with Good Intentions</i></a> is its massive and merciless crushing of this type of hysterical denial, which currently paralyzes all discussion of race relations in America. Considered entirely by itself, this achievement makes his book the most important to be published on the subject for many years. In this area, experience shows that it is not enough to be mugged by reality. Footnotes are apparently necessary as well. And Taylor provides 1,339 of them, quarried from a remarkably wide reading of contemporary sources.</p>
<p>Thus it is indeed true that blacks commit most of New York’s violent crime. Even a decade before my wife arrived in Manhattan, by the early 1970s, blacks already made up over 60 per cent of those arrested for violent crime, but only 20 per cent of the city’s population. And more recently, for example, black men have been responsible for over 85 per cent of the felonies committed against New York City cabbies, as many as 17 of whom are murdered each year. Nationwide, blacks—although only 12 per cent of the population—account for 64 per cent of all violent-crime arrests and 71 per cent of all robbery arrests.</p>
<p>But isn’t this because the police are racist? Apparently not. Taylor hunts down and extirpates all such infinitely regressing excuses, which have for too long substituted for thought in American political discourse. In this case, for example, he proves via a closely reasoned analysis, based on witness reports and arrest patterns for burglaries, traffic violations and drunkenness, that policemen of all races are, if anything, more lenient with criminals of a different race from themselves. (Which, of course, is just what you would expect, given current political pressures.)</p>
<p>Nor is the disparity caused by middle-class law enforcers over-concentrating on street crime. In 1990, blacks were nearly three times as likely as whites to be arrested for white-collar crimes such as forgery, counterfeiting, and embezzlement. And, finally and conclusively, blacks themselves are responsible for 73 per cent of all justified, self-defense killings. The vast majority of the people they kill are other blacks.</p>
<p>A fascinating Orwellian double-think enabled my wife’s hostess to evade this reality—although in her conduct she certainly took account of it every day on Manhattan’s streets. But this doublethink is no mere harmless self-delusion. As in 1984, it requires the constant support of an extraordinary censorship and self-censorship.</p>
<p>Media bias is a subject that easily becomes boring to sophisticates. But the inversions of truth here documented by Taylor are so extreme as to be pathological. Thus he is able to show that every one of the recent alleged white-racist atrocities—Howard Beach, Bensonhurst, Rodney King—had black-on-white analogies that went virtually unreported, although often far worse. For example, Taylor tracks several years of self-feeding press references to the heinous scandal of a white Stanford student hanging a caricatured blackface Beethoven on the door of a black student (who, as it happens, had insisted Beethoven was black). An entire “campus racism” industry has been called into existence on the strength of such trivia. But who has heard of the four black University of Arizona football players, three of them on scholarships, whose hobby of beating up lone campus whites landed them in jail in 1989?</p>
<p>Or for that matter of the Miami-based Yahweh cult, whose leader was convicted in 1992 for causing his followers to kill numerous “white devils”—without benefit of even a fraction of the network prime time devoted to endless reruns of the (dishonestly edited) King-beating video.</p>
<p>This powerful combination of internal and external compulsion is literally able to turn black into white. Thus in 1987 Tawana Brawley, the black teenager who claimed she had been abducted by a white gang, was able, despite the increasing absurdity of her attorneys’ allegations, to focus the attention of the entire country on the supposedly grave issue of white-on-black rape. But in fact it was a complete chimera. In 1988, there were fewer than ten [PB in 2000: in fact, probably a few score] cases of white-on-black rape—as opposed to 9,405 cases of black-on-white rape. Taylor reports that black men appear three to four times more likely to commit rape than whites, and more than sixty times more likely to rape a white than a white is likely to rape a black.</p>
<p>Taylor’s storm of statistics puts in perspective the view that blacks themselves are the chief victims of black crime. That claim is almost true. In America, blacks account for just under half of murder victims. Any decent person will feel a particular sympathy for respectable black people who are likely to suffer the effects both of black crime and of white suspicion prompted by black crime. But their plight is merely one consequence—though a harsh one—of the crisis of black society. Homicide is now the leading cause of death for black men between 15 and 44; one in four black men in their twenties is either in jail, on probation, or on parole. Syphilis is fifty times more prevalent among blacks than among whites; black children are twice as likely as whites to die in their first year.</p>
<p>And this black crisis still disproportionately hurts whites. Black criminals choose white victims in more than half of their violent crime; the average black criminal seems over 12 times more likely to kill a white than vice versa.</p>
<p>The second major contribution of Taylor’s book is its frontal assault on the universal assumption that “white racism” is to blame for everything. In effect, he proposes a logical-positivist’s test: since this racism is (as he demonstrates) publicly illegal, privately undetectable in opinion polls, and does not seem materially to affect the economic status of blacks once that status is adjusted for education and other variables, in what sense does it exist?</p>
<p>Taylor documents in immense detail that the U.S., far from suppressing its blacks and poor, in fact subsidizes them, publicly and privately, including more than $2.5 trillion in federal moneys alone since the 1960s. This, notoriously, has done little good and much ill. But it is hardly the behavior of a racist society—unless liberal politicians, welfare bureaucrats, and academics have deliberately sought to destroy black society by spreading dependency and pauperism.</p>
<p>The truth may set us free. But it can also make us sick. Many people will unquestionably find Taylor’s ruthless exposition of black failure more than they can stomach. One such is the Institute for Justice’s Clint Bolick, who has written very sensibly about civil rights, but who recently reproached Taylor in the Wall Street Journal for dismissing “the continuing impact of racism, which most blacks face every day of their lives.”</p>
<p>Grant that blacks suffer occasional slights, crude name-calling, and some discrimination. But how damaging are these compared to the self-inflicted wounds of black America? And what prompts this white behavior? Is endemic white racism any more reasonable an explanation for the situation than endemic black criminality and the defensive nervous hostility it produces among whites?</p>
<p>“Race is the great American dilemma,” Taylor writes, echoing Gunnar Myrdal’s famous survey, An American Dilemma. Nearly fifty years later, Myrdal’s panacea of integration, equality, and confident social engineering has been followed by disaster. This news could not be more unwelcome. It is hardly surprising that both Left and (alleged) Right prefer to cling to the myth of a culpable—but therefore at least in theory correctable—white racist America.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
